# Gönüllü, Abdullah Faruk

## Software Developer, Systems Engineer, Project Manager

+90 544 550 5541 | af@gonul.lu | Ankara, TURKEY

#### **Resume Summary**

Systems engineer with 10+ years of engineering, process and product planning and management expertise. Passionate about design, architecture and software engineering paradigms, constantly learning and sharing. Interested in everything about software development, currently focused in cloud applications. Looking to put my skills and experience to a new challenge in software industry.

## **Skills Summary**

Language Turkish (mother tongue): excellent written and verbal communication

English: excellent written and verbal communication (TOEFL 103/120)

German: excellent written, very good verbal communication (DSH 90/100, C2 level)

Management Systems Engineering, Project Management, Process Design & Management, Quality

Assurance, Business Development

CS Algorithms, RDBMS, OOP, MVC, SOLID, Software Architecture

**Technical** HTML, CSS, SCSS, JS, React, C#, .NET Core, Wordpress

Design CAD, Graphic Design, UI/UX Design, Illustrator

#### **Education**

2010-2012 M.Sc., Technische Universität Darmstadt, Mechanical Engineering

(unfinished) Area of Studies: Ergonomics, Work and Process Organization, Product Development,

Reliability, Industrial Production Management

2002-2008 B.Sc., Middle East Technical University, Aerospace Engineering

Area of Studies: Core Engineering, Core Aerospace Engineering, Interdisciplinary

Engineering, Systems & Control Engineering, Project Management

#### **Experience**

2018 - Consultant – TUGBA, Ankara

**Present** (Companywide Process Level Improvement, Digitalization, IT Infrastructure Design)

Trained personnel on process design and improvement. Designed key processes and supervised the design of support processes. Coordinated the situation, demand and requirement analysis of the IT infrastructure.

2015-2016 Sectoral Director – TUBITAK TEYDEB, Ankara

(Sectoral R&D Policy and Strategy Planning and Governance)

Administered a yearly grant budget of ~60M USD for industrial R&D projects.

Oversaw assessment, evaluation and monitoring of more than 9000 projects.

2014 QA Team Lead – TUBITAK UZAY, Ankara

(Quality Assurance, Project QA Management)

Participated in several R&D projects. Coordinated structural reorganization of the expanding institute. Collaborated in CMMI appraisal procedures.

## 2012 - 2014 Project Manager – TUBITAK TEYDEB, Ankara

(Project Assessment, Project Management, Process Design and Improvement)
Assessed more than 1000 R&D projects for eligibility to government grants.
Monitored approved projects. Participated in the internal process design and improvement activities.

#### 2011 - 2012 Business Developer – MKG Technology Inc., Ankara

(Business Dev., Lead Management, Product Management, Quality Assurance) Worked as an R&D engineer. Carried out the management, planning, business development tasks of the startup. Designed and installed the quality management system. Designed and documented the core processes.

## 2010 - 2011 Research Assistant – Technische Universität Darmstadt, Darmstadt

(Verification and Validation of Simulation Models)

Research and Assessment of Verification and Validation models for the postgraduate study of verification and validation of simulation of lateral acceleration in automobiles. Designed the verification and validation models in MATLAB.

## 2009 R&D Engineer – MAKIM Co., Ankara

(Project Management, IT Infrastructure Management, Core Engineering Activities) Worked as an R&D engineer for several projects, prepared the application dossiers and periodical reports of the TUBITAK TEYDEB projects of the company. Designed, set up and maintained the intranet, file server, mail server and firewall of the company. Designed and maintained the website of the company

## 2007 - 2008 QA Engineer – YD Software Inc., Ankara

(Quality Assurance, Quality Control)

Designed and developed processes, methods and procedures for company's software development life cycle, as well as written the documentation of the products (e.g. user manuals, project dossiers, etc.)

## 2008 Assistant Project Manager – SEHA Engineering Inc., Ankara

(Project Management, Supply Chain Management, Account Management)
Been responsible for several government contracts throughout their life cycle, i.e. from tender application to contract closeout.

## 2006 Intern – TURKTRAKTOR, Ankara

(R&D Engineering Change Management, Engineering Design Process Management) Proposed several engineering change orders for ongoing tractor platforms, which are later reviewed and approved. This opportunity is proposed by myself, which later became a standard internship activity of the company.

#### 2006 Intern – TURKISH AIRLINES TECHNIC – Istanbul Ataturk Airport – Istanbul

(Quality Assurance, Engine Maintenance Process Management)

Participated in the repair, maintenance and quality assurance procedures for commercial turbo jet engines in engine maintenance workshop.

## **Hobbies & Interests**

Intellectual Bitcoin, Economics, Leadership, Entrepreneurship, Complexity

**Computer** Gaming, Game Dev., Online Content Creation

**Literature** Writing poems and short stories

Owner, editor-in-chief, designer, page-setter of a nation-wide published literature

magazine "yumuşakge" between 2009-2012.

Published poems and short stories in several magazines

Lifestyle Sourdough Baking, Backyard Vegetable Gardening, Tabletop Games, Homeopathy,

Football, Cinema

## References

Available upon request.